venturesafrica.com 2015-02-24

# Ventures Africa | Privacy Policy

****_As of January 22, 2014_

Ventures Publishing International (“Ventures” or “we”) is committed to protecting your privacy.  We have adopted this privacy policy to help you understand how we collect, use, protect and disclose information that is collected from visitors of our website [www.ventures-africa.com](http://www.ventures-africa.com/) and/or our mobile application (collectively, the “Site”).

By using the Site, you agree to the terms and conditions of this privacy policy (the “ **Policy** ”).  We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time, for any reason and without prior notice.  Further, you choose to access the Site at your own initiative and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations that may apply to you.

**Please be aware that any information that you provide and we collect through the Site shall be transferred to, processed and stored in the United States and might be transferred to other countries that might not provide the same level of data protection as your home country. By using the Site, you consent to such collection, processing, transfer and storage of information to the United States and such other countries.**

**Note Regarding the Use of This Site by Children:**  The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and such individuals should not provide Personally Identifiable Information through the Site.

**Collecting Information**

Optional Information.  The Site collects information you provide directly to us when you use certain Site functions.  When you view the Site, you are not required to provide information directly, however when you use certain functions, such as registering for specific services or content, you may have the option of providing the following:

  * contact information, such as your name, email address, postal address, phone number, gender, year of birth
  * profile information, username, password and password reminder questions;
  * information you post in community discussions and other interactive online features;
  * search queries you conduct on the Site; and
  * correspondence you send to us.

Automatic Information.  When you visit the Site, certain information is collected automatically using widely available technology.  Such information may include your:

  * computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * browser type and operating system;
  * bandwidth speed and information about the software programs that are installed on your computer;
  * activities such as: the web pages you visit (and any immediately prior to and after you came to the Site), participation in community discussions on the Site, links and advertisements that you view and click on within the Site; and
  * aggregated data about email click-through rates and user video viewing, standard server log information, and information collected through HTML cookies, Flash cookies, web beacons, and similar _technologies_.  Location information may also be collected if you use the GPS feature on your mobile device, however you have the opportunity to disable this function when you first use the Site on your mobile device.  If you disable this function you may not have access to certain Site features that require geographic location.

Information from Third Parties.  We may access information about you from third-party sources and platforms (such as social networking sites, databases, online marketing firms, and ad targeting firms), including:

  * via third-party social networking services (such as Facebook Connect or Twitter) that you choose to access through the Site, and your username, _profile picture, birthday, email address and connection lists_ for those services;
  * demographic data, such as age range, gender, and interests;
  * advertisement interaction and viewing data, such as ad click-through rates and information about how many times you viewed a particular ad; and
  * unique identifiers, including mobile device identification numbers and GPS information, that can identify the physical location of such devices in accordance with applicable law.

The Site may also combine the information that we collect with information we obtain from third-party sources.  Please remember that we do not control the privacy policies of third-party services that you may be connected to (such as Facebook and Twitter); we encourage you to read their privacy policies as well.

**Use of Information**

Ventures may use your information in the following ways:

  * to fulfill your requests for products and services and respond to your questions and comments;
  * for editorial purposes, such as in connection with our news reporting;
  * to contact you to provide information about the Site or other products or services in which we believe you may be interested;
  * to manage your account;
  * to perform analyses to improve the quality of our Site, services and business, including through surveys and questionnaires;
  * to deliver targeted advertising;
  * to prevent illegal activities and to protect our rights and the rights of others, including by enforcing our Terms of Use; and
  * as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

Ventures values your privacy and shares information only under certain circumstances.  Information you provide through the Site may be may be made available to other companies, applications or people in the following situations:

  * with authorized service providers for the purpose of helping us provide services on the Site or perform business functions for us, such as sending emails or hosting web services (but these service providers are not permitted to use personally identifiable information that we provide for any purpose other than to provide service to us);
  * with our corporate affiliates, licensees, and contractors;
  * with select third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, although you may choose up front and at no cost that we not share personally identifiable information that we have collected about you for these purposes by emailing us at [editor@ventures-africa.com](mailto:editor@ventures-africa.com)
  * to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process requests for cooperation from law enforcement or government agencies, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or to enforce, protect or defend our rights or property or the rights or property of others or public safety;
  * when we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law;
  * to enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements, such as in connection with a corporate transaction;
  * as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent; and,
  * if you submit content to the Site, such as commenting on a story or chatting with other users, any information that you submit will become public. It may also become accessible through search engines or, if you sign in using credentials from a third-party social networking service such as Facebook or Twitter, to users on that service.

**Questions or Comments**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Policy, you may contact us at: editor@ventures-africa.com

Total Views: 1501 ,
